(Transcribed by TurboScribe. Go Unlimited to remove this message.) The stars are gone.
The planets have disappeared.
There were barely enough of us left to give the end a
name.
The Quiet Rapture.
Supplies dwindle.
Infrastructure crumbles.
Too few to rebuild.
Too many to feed.
Humanity decays.
But don't despair, my sons.
I tell you now that there is more to these moons than
meets the eye.
The consolidation.
They hide their technology, their people.
They won't tell you what they found, but I will.
One moon stands apart from the rest.
And in the darkness of that moon, an ocean of blood.
Beginning the descent.
Exploration of AT-5 underway.
How's it looking down there, convict?
Ready to do some good for a change?
Yeah.
Let's get this done.
Roger that.
Cruising depth in roughly two minutes.
Stand by.
I'm seeing some voltage irregularities on the instrument, so keep an eye
out for sparks or flames or anything like that.
Flames?
Why would there be flames?
I don't know.
That's why I warned you.
You did test this thing, right?
This is the test.
But you're welded in as tight as we can make it in
that ship's tank.
Just keep an eye on your depth while you're down there.
The terrain can be unpredictable, so make sure you're not wandering down
too far into the red.
It can take pressure, but there's a limit.
I'm starting to feel it, that glass.
All right.
Closing porthole shielding.
Hey, what is it exactly you want me to find?
You haven't told me what it is.
We don't know.
You're the first one down.
All we have are surface scans.
That's why you're there.
Well, one of the reasons.
You know, we salvaged that glass from Filament Station.
A lot of scratch on it.
Right?
Pretty lucky.
Funny how some things survive and others don't.
Approaching maximum depth.
30 seconds.
Hey, um, hey, are you hearing this?
Hello?
Hey.
Uh, hey, you said not to go into the red.
We're in the red.
Ready to lose radio signal.
Head to the coordinates, the map, and cap it, and as instructed,
we'll consider your pay as served.
Be careful.
Love your own.
No.
Hey!
You can't be serious.
Fuck me.
One minute.
Fifty.
Camera.
That's useful.
Oxygen.
Twenty-six.
Way off.
It's not even on the map.
Maybe.
Hey, what do I do if I find something not on the
map?
You're not just pretending you can't hear me, right?
Why is it so fucking hot down here?
I'm here.
Uh, dude, I, I, I don't know.
Was that you?
What is it?
You didn't tell me that there would be anything down here.
Calm down.
Just tell me there's a problem with the ship.
Do you know if the ship is damaged before we send you
back down?
Back?
Back down?
No.
No fucking way!
I'm done.
So just bring me back up and throw me in prison.
I'm not doing this!
If they're damaged, tell me if there's a problem with the sub,
because if you fell, the hull could be punctured, which means a
leak, which means flooding, which means you die.
Um, um, it seems fine.
Good.
I can't see much, but it seems like the hull is in
one piece, so we're going to check on your progress while we
wait for the ocean to settle back down.
Hey, do you think we can get any pictures?
I mean, you could get a couple, maybe.
Yeah, well, it might take a while to settle, so go ahead.
Uh, settle?
What does that mean?
Um, is that why everything was shaking?
Essentially, yeah.
The bottom isn't exactly rock, just layers of congealed blood and gas
bubbles.
That's why I said it wasn't stable.
What?
You may want to see this.
That's the most recent picture.
Holy shit.
Convicts, you're...
Did you find a skeleton?
Yeah.
This could just be rock skin.
Can you get me a higher resolution?
Look at this.
Yes, I am.
Convict, are you absolutely sure that it was a skeleton?
Yeah.
I've seen a skeleton before.
How stupid do you think I am?
We're pulling you up.
Stand by.
Huh?
Hey, so, uh, so what's the deal?
Am I done?
How's your afternoon?
Any leaks?
Uh, um, uh, yeah, I'm down a lot, but, yeah, maybe.
There might be a leak.
There was some blood dripping in, and then there's some kind of
liquid building up on the walls.
I don't know what it was.
It's just a condensation.
I know a condensation.
Look, it doesn't matter.
You just warn the next person that goes down what I found.
There's something alive down there.
Hey, yeah, so I found something, right?
Something good?
We downloaded the picture.
Sure looks like a skeleton to me.
Come on, get me out of here.
You can't.
Like I said, you're welded in.
You take your time getting in.
Another slip might go somewhere that we can't get, so I'm going
to give you something to take a sample.
Hey!
You're not listening to me!
There's something else!
Okay, it's not like I don't want the deal, all right?
I want the deal.
I want to make...
It's not worth it.
It's not.
It's not worth it for me.
It's not worth it for you.
Fawning over this skeleton, but you're not hearing me when I say
there's something else.
Something alive.
There might just be.
Right up front.
All you got to do is point it in the right direction.
Once it makes contact, it should be able to grab onto something
and hold on tight.
So what am I supposed to do?
Just ram it?
Pretty much.
You can't be serious.
I am.
You'll have to hit it hard, too.
Hard enough to make sure that it catches.
You won't be able to see if it works, so no second
chances.
Okay, so you don't just want me to ram it.
You want me to ram it at full speed?
Why play games?
Why go through all this trouble?
If you want me dead so bad, why don't you just do
it yourself?
This is the best we have.
This is bigger than any of us, so just do your job.
My job?
Oh, I'm sorry.
The handcuffs must have confused me.
I didn't realize this was voluntary!
Hey!
Don't walk away!
If this don't bond you, why aren't you going down there?
Hey!
Go down, come back, and then I'm free!
That was the deal!
How many times are you going to use me before you let
me go?
Oh, good.
You can hear me.
Now get someone else for your suicide mission, because I'm not going
to let this radiation you sent over here fuck!
It's not a normal camera.
You can't see through blood, so you need x-rays to get
through.
I didn't know that.
Okay, it's on.
Hey, let me show you.
I didn't know that.
No, wait.
Look, I'm sorry, but maybe if you had talked to me, this
wouldn't have happened!
I'm just going to sit here.
Come on, guy, back together.
Don't be too upset.
Kind of a fair play after what you did.
Oh, shit, are you still alive?
Fuck off.
Ah, there you are.
All right, beginning the descent.
Uh, hey, you, uh, you gotta close the portal shield, man.
Hello?
Convict, this is Sirius.
Close the shield.
Who is this?
Where's the other one?
The other one, you're talking about Jack, the guy you irradiated?
Well, Captain's taking him to medical, so I'm in charge now.
And my first order is close the fucking shield.
Why can't you do it?
It's not responsible, which is why we have you.
Is it closed?
Yes, it's closed.
Now, we're going to give you about 30 minutes to go get
that sample before we pull you back up.
Don't worry, I know ramming it sounds scary, but the salvage clods
and most of the impact of those welds aren't going anywhere.
This Jack is good at his job.
Or, let me repeat, well, he was good at his job.
You didn't think it was important to tell me that your camera
was a radiation gun?
No, I wouldn't.
That shouldn't have happened at all.
Well, the camera's wired into the black box, but I must have
wired it into the back of that.
We were in a rush.
Right.
Things are somehow faster when I don't know what I'm doing.
You know, honestly, if I were in charge, you would know more.
I'd actually give us the results on a nod.
I'm just a cognitive machine.
But, you know, this is bigger than us.
So I've heard.
Well, man, can we just agree this is important?
The filament station was a bad loss, but imagine if we could
actually rebuild it.
Even you could be a part of that.
I read your report.
You surrendered.
Still fooling by Eden's bullshit?
All their talk about the last tree.
It's not about the tree.
Right.
But Eden gave me a tattoo.
The COI made me burn it off.
I didn't choose either of them.
I still get a scar.
Since the Quiet Rapture.
None of us get a choice.
Hey, look at that.
There's at least something we can agree on.
To be honest with you, Captain's had a consolidated stick up her
ass in the Quiet Rapture.
But, uh, she cares about her crew.
Some more than others, but, you know.
Yeah, right.
Can you at least tell me if this thing is blasting me
with radiation?
No, the hull's fucked up.
Food, air.
We need this.
It's not just the COI.
All of us.
We need this.
Shit.
This is
not
an expedition.
It's an execution.
When they put you in here, they don't want you to return.
And even if you do, and even if they keep their promises,
what freedom waits for you?
A few dying ships and a sea of dead stars.
If there is still hope, it lies beyond the veil.
Hope in this void is as illusionary as the starlight.
I will choose to breathe my last here.
At the bottom of an ocean.
Unseen.
Unheard.
Uncontrolled.